class QuestionModel{
  final String question;
  final List<String> options;
  final correctAnswerIndex;
  final String Solution;

  const QuestionModel({
    required this.question,
    required this.options,
    required this.correctAnswerIndex,
    required this.Solution,
  });
}


List<QuestionModel> ConstructionalMaterialsEngineering= [
  QuestionModel(question: "1. Which of these materials is a primary component of ordinary Portland cement?",
      options: [
        "Limestone",
        "Gypsum",
        "Clay",
        "Sand"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Limestone is a key component in the production of ordinary Portland cement."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "2. What is the primary function of adding aggregates to concrete?",
      options: [
        "Enhancing workability",
        "Increasing durability",
        "Improving bonding",
        "Controlling setting time"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "Aggregates are added to concrete to improve its durability and strength."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "3. Which of these materials is known for high tensile strength and flexibility in construction?",
      options: [
        "Steel",
        "Aluminum",
        "Copper",
        "Wood"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Steel is used for its high tensile strength and flexibility in construction applications."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "4. What does the term 'efflorescence' refer to in construction materials?",
      options: [
        "Heat resistance of materials",
        "A crystalline deposit on surfaces",
        "The tensile strength of materials",
        "The level of material workability"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "Efflorescence is a crystalline deposit that can form on surfaces of masonry and concrete."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "5. Which material is renowned for its high thermal insulation properties in construction?",
      options: [
        "Fiberglass",
        "Concrete",
        "Brick",
        "Aluminum"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Fiberglass is used for its excellent thermal insulation properties in construction."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "6. What mineral provides waterproofing in the manufacture of asphalt roofing shingles?",
      options: [
        "Calcite",
        "Gypsum",
        "Granite",
        "Slate"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: "Slate is a mineral that aids in providing waterproofing in asphalt shingles."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "7. Which process in concrete production helps prevent the formation of large air bubbles in the mix?",
      options: [
        "Curing",
        "Mixing",
        "Vibration",
        "Compaction"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: "Compaction is key to preventing the formation of large air bubbles in concrete."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "8. In reinforced concrete, what is the primary role of the steel reinforcement bars?",
      options: [
        "Provide insulation",
        "Improve fire resistance",
        "Resist tensile forces",
        "Enhance durability"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "Steel reinforcement bars in concrete resist tensile forces, adding strength."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "9. Which of these materials is primarily used in rapid construction due to its lightness and strength?",
      options: [
        "Aluminum",
        "Fiberglass",
        "Concrete",
        "Steel"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Aluminum is utilized for its strength and lightness in rapid construction."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "10. What gives gypsum board its fire-resistant properties in building interiors?",
      options: [
        "Paper covering",
        "Glass fibers",
        "Fire-retardant chemicals",
        "Embedded steel bars"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "Fire-retardant chemicals in gypsum board provide fire-resistant properties."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "11. In construction, what type of wood is known for its resistance to decay and insects?",
      options: [
        "Birch",
        "Pine",
        "Cedar",
        "Maple"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "Cedar wood is valued for its resistance to decay and insects."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "12. Which material is known for its exceptional load-bearing capability and durability in bridges?",
      options: [
        "Aluminum",
        "Concrete",
        "Timber",
        "Steel"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: "Steel is used for its load-bearing capability and durability in bridge construction."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "13. Which material is most commonly used for electrical insulation in construction?",
      options: [
        "Copper",
        "Aluminum",
        "Rubber",
        "Fiberglass"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: "Fiberglass is primarily used for electrical insulation in construction."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "14. What gives clay bricks their characteristic color and hardness after firing?",
      options: [
        "Iron oxide",
        "Cobalt",
        "Zinc",
        "Aluminum oxide"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Iron oxide in the clay gives bricks their color and hardness upon firing."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "15. Which material is widely used for insulating external building walls?",
      options: [
        "Brick",
        "Fiberglass",
        "Steel",
        "Concrete"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "Fiberglass is a common choice for insulating external walls in buildings."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "16. What type of material provides an effective vapor barrier in construction?",
      options: [
        "Concrete",
        "Plywood",
        "Asphalt",
        "Polyethylene sheeting"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: "Polyethylene sheeting is used as an effective vapor barrier in construction."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "17. What type of aggregate is commonly used in the production of lightweight concrete?",
      options: [
        "Pumice",
        "Limestone",
        "Granite",
        "Marble"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "Pumice is a frequently used aggregate in lightweight concrete production."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "18. What mineral component contributes to the strength of Portland cement?",
      options: [
        "Calcium sulfate",
        "Quartz",
        "Alumina",
        "Gypsum"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "Alumina contributes to the strength of Portland cement."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "19. What is the primary function of rebar in concrete construction?",
      options: [
        "Reduce cracking",
        "Improve aesthetics",
        "Resist compression",
        "Enhance tensile strength"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: "Rebar enhances the tensile strength of concrete, preventing cracking."
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "20. What is the role of the admixture known as a plasticizer in concrete production?",
      options: [
        "Increase workability",
        "Accelerate setting time",
        "Enhance insulation",
        "Improve durability"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "A plasticizer in concrete production increases workability and flow."
  ),


  ];